

Vitor Pedro

Software Engineer

I started my career as an IT Trainee where I worked in interesting projects and gained experience with different technologies. I have been working as a C++ software engineer and I participate in all the phases of the software development lifecycle process. I am passionate about developing apps that can make a difference in people's lives.

vitor@vitorpedro.com



917088884



vitormcpedro



vitorpedro.com

Technical Highlights

General programming: C, C++

Front End: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery

Back End: PHP, MySQL

GIT

Scrum

Linux

Languages

Portuguese Native or Bilingual

English Upper-intermediate

Interests

Software engineering

Web technologies

Information systems

Playing piano | Mountain biking

Work Experience

04/2013 - Present

Coimbra, Portugal

Software Engineer

Perceive3D (Startup company)

Technologies used: C, C++, OpenGL, OpenCV, Cuda, Eigen, QT, GIT, Linux

Tasks/Achievements

- Development of real time image processing applications for medical devices using C++ and Cuda (responsible for the in.sight product: http://perceive3d.com/en/products)
- Identification of technical solutions for new business requirements
- Responsible for the implementation of SCRUM methodology in the company
- Project planning (time estimation, definition of goals for each release and task assignment)
- Software documentation (software requirements specification, architectural design and development plan) according to IEC 62304

09/2012 - 04/2013

Coimbra, Portugal

Research Fellow

Institute of Systems and Robotics - University of Coimbra

Technologies used: C, Matlab, Python, Latex

Tasks/Achievements

- Development of a visual recognition system for localization purposes by establishing correspondences between a query image and a database of geo-referenced images constituting a topological visual map
- 09/2011 08/2012 Lisbon, Portugal

IT Trainee

Optimus Comunicações SA

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, jQuery Mobile, Perl, Outsystems, Confluence, Salesforce

Tasks/Achievements

- Web development
- Design and development of a carsharing web mobile app
- Definition of software requirements for web applications
- Software development using the Outsystems platform
- Reporting (SAP Business Objects and Salesforce)

Certificates

- Full Stack Web Development Certification Free Code Camp (2016 Present)
 My Portfolio: www.vitorpedro.com
- Image and video processing (introduction level) (02/2014 03/2014) Provided by Duke University through Coursera inc
- Machine Learning (10/2013 01/2014) Provided by Stanford University through Coursera inc

Personal Projects

■ Events Finder iOS App (02/2016 - 08/2016)

■ More information on www.eventsfinderapp.com

- Find events based on a search guery. Uses the Facebook API.
- Education

09/2006 - 08/2011

Coimbra, Portugal

MSc, Electrical and Computer Engineering (17) University of Coimbra

Achievements

Best 3% students of the course award (2007 - 2010) Awards given by FCTUC - University of Coimbra